Guide to the Fortunoff Video Archive for Holocaust Testimonies Collection of Related Documents and Ephemera
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Moses D., 1932-1950; HVT-4098 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  Contains newspaper clippings; correspondence written between 1939 and 1944 regarding Moses D.'s legal efforts to remove his siblings from foster care; and copies of identification cards/documents 1932-1950.
- Alfred K., 1988; HVT-4111 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  Contains a summary of Alfred K.'s job history; a copy of his resume; a business card for Alfred K. at Zooba; an autobiography of his life between 1931 and 1951; a copy of remarks made by Alfred K. at the Matzeva unveiling of Peter Goldring in Miami, Florida; and a copy of remarks made by Alfred K. at his own retirement party.
- Peter H., 2002; HVT-4240 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  Contains a spiral-bound pictorial/prose personal message detailing Peter H.'s Jewish heritage including memorial, history, rabbis, Ahlem, Schusters, Wolfes, and Auschwitz sections.
- Theodore M., 2000; HVT-4242 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  Contains a personal memoir entitled "Surviving Lapac: the true story of one man's escape to freedom," documenting Theodore M.'s experiences during the Holocaust.
- Alice F., 1990; HVT-4264 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  Contains a brief autobiography of Alice F.'s life through 1946, and a Reader's Digest article on Ted Aplin and the Bergen-Belsen displaced persons camp.
- Maria S., 2003; HVT-4266 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  Contains a CD: "Memories and Dreams: A Holocaust Survivor Remembers. The Poetry of Maria Szapszewicz."
- Suzanne R., 2003; HVT-4270 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Contains a memoir of Suzanne R.'s experiences through 1950 and her reflections on her trip back to Paris in 2002 and her visiting of locations where she spent time during WWII.
- Herman L., 1980; HVT-4289 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Contains an excerpt from the introductory chapter of Herman L.'s book Mostly in the Line of Duty: Thirty Years with Books, which details his experiences as a prisoner during WWII.
- Edith E., 1999; HVT-4293 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Contains newspaper clipping featuring a photograph of the family business, and correspondence from the Stiftung Dokumentationsarchiv detailing what happened to her mother and sister.
- Alex P., 1991; HVT-4326 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Contains copies of Alex P.'s plays and memoirs regarding his experiences during WWII, and a written work documenting the lives of eighteen family members who died in 1944 in German concentration camps.
- Luna H., Undated; HVT-4337 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  Contains DVD of Luna H.'s photographs.
- Alice R., Circa 2003; HVT-4367 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  Contains copies of a biographical essay by Alice R. dated August 24, 2003,and a family history essay by her grandson.
- Ernest K., 1941; HVT-4368 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Contains newspaper clippings; a photocopy of the cover of a 1947-1948 issue of "Who's Who Among North American Esperantists" with a brief biography of Ernest K.'s father; a brief autobiography written in German; and a copy of his father's Maccabi identification.
- Eva G., 1935; HVT-4392 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Contains Eva G.'s Deutsches Reich Arbeitsbuch (work book); and her mother's Deutsches Reich Kennkarte (identity card).
- Fran L., 1991; HVT-4395 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Contains newspaper clippings; program and inserts from the Rivkah Laufer Bikur Cholim Annual Luncheon; and publicity by Fran L. regarding her upcoming book The Sacred Covenant.
- Rosa W. (HVT-4397), Samuel W. (HVT-4398), 2004 September 24; HVT-4397 and HVT-4398 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  Contains notice of an exhibit of photographs of the Bergen-Belsen Displaced Persons Camp at Beth Radom congregation.
- Hyman K., 1999; HVT-4400 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Contains a handwritten, brief autobiography; an edited and updated copy of a transcript of an interview by the Jewish Historical Society of Hartford; and a bound copy of Hyman K.'s personal memoir, entitled "An Unusual Escape to Freedom," documenting his experiences from 1925-1999.
- Claude L., 1971; HVT-4403 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Contains a French document about the experiences of Belgian Jews during WWII, and an English copy of a 1971 speech made in French by Lucien Steinberg about the participation of Jews in the Allied Armies.
- Hannelore H., 1988; HVT-4406 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  Contains two copies of a personal memoir regarding Hannelore H.'s family's arrest, in March 1943, by the Nazis.
- Gerald F., 2006; HVT-4407 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  Contains printout from Gerald F.'s website featuring his diary entries during WWII, and a copy of an SEPM Foundation publication, Saxa Loquntur (Rocks Speak): The Life and Times of the Geologist Gerald M. Friedman.
- Martin S., 2002; HVT-4412 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  Contains two copies of a publication by The Manhattan College Holocaust Center entitled, Reflections of the Soul: Martin Spett's Holocaust Experiences.
- Michael S., 2008; HVT-4415 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  Contains a copy of the preface and Appendix A from Franco Modigliani: A Mind That Never Rests.
- Ben L., Undated; HVT-4431 (Box 5, Folder 13a)
  Contains a copy of a scanned Westchester Jewish Chronicle newspaper photograph of Jewish partisans from Vilna after the city's liberation; 3 copies of a scanned photograph of the living quarters of the Jewish Partisans in the Rudnicki Forest south of Vilna.
- Miscellaneous Holocaust-related printed ephemera not associated with specific testimonies
  - Kampf um's Dritte Reich: Eine Historische Bilderfolge, cigarette card album, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Nazi-era propaganda album owned by Gustav Wollschind (?), containing photographs and cigarette cards depicting Adolf Hitler, other National Socialist leaders, and scenes depicting rallies and war preparations. In German.
  - Printed ephemera relating to Jews in Nazi-era and post-war Germany, 1938-circa 1945 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Contains identification documents from Landsberg Displaced Persons Camp for Josef Wajsman; Deutsches Reich Reisepass (identification paper) for Siegfried Risewz, stamped with a red J to identify the bearer as a Jew; postal receipt document from Bonn.
  - Journal or story of emigration to Israel (photocopy), title (stenciled) and handwritten marginalia in Hebrew, text written in Hungarian (32 pages), Circa 1940s (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Letters (photocopies) in German dealing with transports and other topics, written to the Raab family, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 3)